Hello, everyone.
My name is Minko Gechev.
I'm working on Angular at Google Today.
In this video, I'll want to show you how you can use Angular
DevTools to preview the structure of your application and
profile its performance.
Angular DevTools is the Chrome DevTools extension that you
can download from the Chrome Webstar.
You can find a link in the description below.
When you install Angular DevTools, you can go to extensions and pin it.
The next step is to open an application running in development
mode. See how the color of the icon changed to red, indicating
we can debug the application.
Now let us open Chrome DevTools and find the Angular tab.
Here.
We can preview the componentry of the application.
Once we select a component, we can find its metadata, properties,
inputs, and outputs in the right panel, and we can modify
them directly from the UI.
Now let us navigate to the profiler tab and start recording
change detection events.
We can preview change detection cycles as they occur in real
time. Each bar in the timeline corresponds to a separate
change detection cycle.
We can find how much time we spend in change detection and
Now let us open Chrome DevTools and find the Angular tab.
Here.
We can preview the componentry of the application.
Once we select a component, we can find its metadata, properties,
inputs, and outputs in the right panel, and we can modify
them directly from the UI.
Now let us navigate to the profiler tab and start recording
change detection events.
We can preview change detection cycles as they occur in real
time. Each bar in the timeline corresponds to a separate
change detection cycle.
We can find how much time we spend in change detection and
whether the current cycle costs any frame drops.
We can also preview the estimated frame rates and what triggered
change detection.
At the bottom, we can preview the components we spent the
most time in.
When we select a bar, we can see further details for the
particular component.
To better understand the applications execution, we can switch
between the default bar chart view or the two alternative
views Flame graph and Tree map.
That is all I have for you today.
Head to Anguorio DevTools to find more advanced Angular DevTools
features. Thank you very much for watching and happy coding.